You are being watched.
The government has
a secret system--
a machine that spies on
you every hour of every day.
I designed the machine
to detect acts of terror
but it sees
everything--
violent crimes involving
ordinary people.
The government considered
these people irrelevant.
We don't.
Hunted by the authorities,
we work in secret.
You'll never find us.
But victim or perpetrator,
if your number's
up, we'll find you.
Everything's in place.
Good, let's begin.
He does that.
The man likes his privacy.
You can't blame a girl for trying.
It's for you.
Good morning, Ms. Shaw.
Morning.
Beautiful day for a walk.
I suppose.
When you finish yours, could
you join us back at the library?
We have another number.
Detective Carter, right?
Office actually.
Alonzo Quinn.
Cal's Godfather, of course.
I remember you from the funeral.
Your eulogy was beautiful.
Wasn't hard to find beautiful
things to say about Cal.
Chief was keeping me
apprised of his case.
Says they're looking at a couple
of Carl Elias' men as the shooters.
Yes, heard that too.
You think otherwise?
Not sure. But I think
there is more to than that.
My shift is about start.
Don't let me hold you up. It's
nice seeing you again, Office.
Me too. Take care.
It's me.
I think we might still have
a problem with Office Carter.
What's up?
Looking for news on Cal's case.
I haven't heard any.
What about in the database?
- Carter...
- Look, I'd check myself,
but you know they pulled my access.
Yes, they will pull
mine too if they catch me
poking around a case
I'm not assigned to.
Come on, it's important.
Ok. When it clears out a little.
Thanks, Fusco.
I've got our number, Finch.
What do you know about this guy?
Wayne Kruger, 43, married,
Internet entrepreneur,
and founder of a company
called "LifeTrace".
And what's their business?
They marketed themselves as
a "People Search" service,
where their users can look
up old friends or relatives
anyone they've fallen
out of touch with.
Sounds harmless enough.
There is, however,
more to it than that.
Always is.
Their business isn't really
about reconnecting people,
it's about collecting and
selling their information.
He's a data broker.
What kind of data?
Anything you would ever
wanna know about a person
where they live, work, shop, eat,
how much they earn,
how they vote and more.
Then he turns around and sells the
information to businesses, individuals
even the government.
Is that legal?
Technically, data brokers get their
information from public records,
but also from the ways people
reveal themselves online
whether they're aware
or whether they're not.
Sounds a little like your machine.
A principle difference would be
that the machine never
reveals any of its information
beyond the social security number.
So you're not a fan of Kruger's.
People like him are
one of the reasons
I made sure the machine
was impenetrable black box.
Kruger's just entered his building.
He's in Shaw's hands now.
I hope sending her in
there was a good decision.
You doubt her ability
to be discreet?
I doubt her ability to
keep from shooting someone?
I'm in, Finch.
Kruger's got some kind
of big shot meeting.
Gentlemen, we're thrilled
that you're considering us.
We know that Riverton
is a huge retailer
and that you've got your pick
of potential data partners.
We've done
our homework--
or rather peter has
done our homework, and
he says you're one of the
companies we should consider.
I've looked at all the
information you provided,
including the company
profile, growth rate,
consumer analytic statistics,
and data points per target--
Congratulations.
Any problems with
your cover, Ms. Shaw?
Not unless someone asks me to type.
A baby rattle?
I apologize if I
spoiled the surprise.
No, it's all right,
it's just, my wife and I
haven't told anybody
outside the immediate family.
- How did you know?
- Your wine consumption.
- Excuse me?
- It's dropped from two bottles a week
to almost nothing in
the past three months,
And your milk, yogurt, and
cheese consumption has tripled.
The grocery store where you shop.
You're members of their
customer loyalty program.
We created that.
And I thought they
just sent out coupons.
No. Programs like that
are just scratching the
surface of what we can do.
What we're really working
towards here at LifeTrace
is the future,
A future where every
person's needs will be met
because we have all the
information necessary
to meet those needs.
Eating habits to predict diseases.
Compatibility factors
to eliminate loneliness.
And the way we do that is
by getting to know someone,
from the major
events of their lives,
right down to the tiniest
detail of their everyday routine.
Learning everything about a person
allows us to help them
improve their life.
Sounds appealing, but can I ask,
have you run into any issues
with respect to privacy concerns?
Nothing significant.
There are always a few who
take issue with what we do,
but these days, people know,
you can't fight the technology.
And let's be honest, those
crying the loudest about privacy
are probably the ones
trying to hide something.
That's why--
uh, Barry.
- Oh, yeah.
- That's why I put my own profile up on our site.
Anyone can look me up and
see, I've got nothing to hide.
We'll need to work out a
proposal to present to our board.
How would tomorrow
morning work for you?
Sounds great.
Yes, it'll be all
their numbers--
Whatever's going on with this guy,
it sure isn't hurting his business.
I think it's time to look a
little more closely at Mr. Kruger.
People who say they have
nothing to hide almost always do.
Nothing comes up on his record.
Thank you for checking.
I understand you're
back on the day shift.
Yeah, but I'm giving up something
What's that?
My patience.
Good morning.
We'll see.
Before we roll, I just want to say
I'm really looking forward
to working together and--
Laskey,
one, I didn't want to be an F.T.O.,
but it beats being a vampire.
Number two,
When I tell you to do something,
just you do it, no questions.
And number three,
Don't touch my radio. Got it?
Yes, Ma'am.
Carter. Just Carter.
How is it I got stuck
being the office monkey?
I thought you liked being in
the middle of the action, Shaw.
I think I'd see more
action in a tollbooth.
I was just emptying the trash.
No problem.
- I'll come back.
- Okay.
Tell the board we're
meeting tomorrow.
Sure thing, Mr. Kruger.
Quite a stunt you pulled
with the baby rattle.
I'd have told you about it,
but you'd have tried
to talk me out of it.
You're right. We need this deal.
Well, we just got
it. Come on, Barry.
This changes everything.
This puts us on the map.
What is it, Haley?
It's about the party tonight.
I tried to put the restaurant
deposit on your credit card
but it was declined.
What? Why?
I don't know, the bank
wouldn't tell me, I'm sorry.
I'll handle it.
You know, sometimes, I
wish I had an assistant
whose qualifications extended
beyond having a great ass.
I sure hope this
guy's a perpetrator.
Want to go to a party, Shaw?
Only if you promise to
wear something pretty.
Thanks. You.
First, I want to say
it's great of all of you
to make it tonight,
especially my wife Dedee.
Mr. Reese, how's
the Kruger's party?
Delightful.
Have you learned anything?
Just that Kruger's
got a lot of friends,
appears to be happily married,
and Shaw likes truffled quail eggs.
You can't expect me to shoot
somebody on an empty stomach.
I'd prefer you didn't
shoot anyone at all.
What about you,
Finch? Dig anything up?
Yes. Kruger's gone to great lengths
to suppress any bad
publicity about LifeTrace.
Negative blog posts, news articles,
Even a class action lawsuit buried
in non-disclosure agreements,
All scrubbed from the internet.
Sweetheart, I love
you. This is for you.
I've got nothing to hide.
Turn it off. Turn it off, now!
Turn it off!
This somebody's idea of a joke?
Dedee, honey,
I have no id--
Mr. Reese?
Yeah, someone just turned Kruger's
anniversary video into a sex tape.
Oh, my.
Sweetie,
listen--
What are you all looking at?
Go home. The party's over.
Party's over!
Just when things were
getting interesting.
I know, first his
credit cards, now this.
Someone's messing
with Kruger, Finch.
The machine wouldn't
send us his number
if someone just wanted
to humiliate him.
No, we need to find
whoever's behind this
before they come after him again.
Or before Kruger finds them first.
- Finch.
- Ms. Shaw. Is everything all right?
Don't sound so worried, Harold.
I haven't hurt anybody...yet.
Very reassuring. You have news?
I think I know who hijacked
Kruger's anniversary party.
Here's the restaurant's security
camera footage from last night.
A woman dressed as a waiter.
None of the waitstaff
had seen her before.
I might have.
I've been going
through all the parties
to the class action
suit against Kruger.
All of them claim to
have been victimized
when their personal information
was released by LifeTrace.
Victimized how?
Identity theft, harassment,
blackmail, fraud.
Even murder.
Who?
Chloe Harper,
Daughter of the lead
plaintiff, Sherry Harper.
She lost her life to a stalker,
who found her home
address using LifeTrace.
No wonder Kruger
wanted the suit buried.
Detective Fusco is
running background checks
on all of the
plaintiffs as we speak.
Wait, I just found
our mystery waiter.
Her name is Karen Mills.
She lives in Queens.
I'm on my way.
No, stay put, Ms. Shaw.
I'll see if Detective
Carter can help us.
- What did she do?
- Rolled a stop.
Really?
Stay in the car. I got this.
License and registration, please.
Something wrong, Officer?
You could say that.
Why are you coming
after Wayne Kruger?
Don't make me ask twice, Ms. Mills.
I-I got a package.
A package? From who?
I don't know.
It was anonymous.
There was a DVD and
some instructions
on what to do if I
wanted to get back at him.
Why? What did he do to you?
He ruined my life.
How?
I was a paralegal at a law firm.
It's where I met my fiance.
One day, some of
the assistants were
looking people up on
this website, LifeTrace.
They found some pictures.
What kind of pictures?
They were taken
by an ex-boyfriend,
of us, in his bedroom.
And everyone saw them.
My fiance, he...
called off our engagement.
When I got the package,
I saw a chance to make Kruger
feel the humiliation that I felt.
So I took it.
Okay.
I'm gonna let you off with a
warning this time, Ms. Mills.
So long as you take
that package you got
take it to a Detective Lionel
Fusco at the 8th precinct,
and you promise me you'll never
do anything like that again.
Thank you. I won't, Officer.
Good, 'cause the NYPD, we'll know.
Trust me.
Hope you got that.
Mr. Reese?
I heard.
Doesn't sound like
she had anything to do
with the other attacks on Kruger.
Likely done by whoever
sent the anonymous package.
Look, baby, I know you're mad,
but I need you to call me back.
The bank says our
cards have been canceled
and our account's emptied out.
Something's wrong. Just call me.
Haley, will you get my
accountant on the line?
What are you doing?
What's the problem?
My problem?
First saved message.
You know, sometimes, I
wish I had an assistant
whose qualifications extended
beyond having a great ass.
- Where did that come from?
- You, apparently.
Someone is using Kruger's
own words against him.
His office must be bugged.
Screw you, Wayne.
Mr. Hayes?
Mr. Collier.
Mr. Collier, what's going on?
In light of recent developments,
Mr. Deaver doesn't think LifeTrace
is the best partner
for us, after all.
Excuse me.
This is getting
better by the minute.
What the hell happened?
I was hoping you could tell me.
No. No, no, no. You
gotta take the site down.
We already did, but not
before Riverton saw it.
They yanked the deal!
I cannot believe this is happening!
You never said you went
bankrupt, or had a DUI.
That was over ten years
ago. It was expunged.
Is this an arrest warrant?
I was in college. It was dismissed.
Look, this is all ancient history.
It's new to us, and to Riverton.
Someone is screwing with
me. Can't you see that?
Wayne, we think it
might be best if you...
took some time to sort
out your personal issues.
If I took some time?
A leave of absence while
we evaluate our options.
While you evaluate your options?
This is my company, Barry!
And you're the face of it.
And that's now a problem.
Okay,
look--
We already took a vote.
Fine. Fine.
But I'm gonna find out
who's doing this to me.
And then, I'm gonna call Riverton.
I'm gonna fix this.
Looks like Kruger's just been
kicked out of his own company.
Things are escalating
with Kruger, Finch.
We any closer to
finding the perpetrator?
I'm working on it, Mr. Reese.
Hello.
You've hurt a great many people,
- Mr. Kruger.
- What? Who is this?
You need to understand.
Understand what?
You listen to me. If I find
out you're the one responsible--
The elevator's free falling.
Modern elevators do
not freefall, Ms. Shaw.
Tell that to Kruger.
You can't fight the technology.
Somebody has disabled
the auto-safety features.
The elevators aren't
networked. I can't access them.
Kruger made it out, Finch.
Whoever's coming after
him has taken his company,
his money, his marriage.
Soon the only thing left
to take will be his life.
Finch, the call he
got in the elevator,
could you trace it?
No, but whoever
hijacked the elevator
would have needed access to
the building's electrical room.
I do know who cleaned out
Kruger's bank accounts.
- Who?
- Dennis Paulson.
Detective Fusco got his
photo off the phony ID.
He used to cash out
Kruger's accounts.
He's another member of the
class action suit against Kruger,
same as Ms. Mills.
Then we're looking at
multiple perpetrators.
Yes. Paulson lost his
job and was arrested
after LifeTrace
conflated his profile with
that of a serial rapist who
happened to have the same name.
Hate it when that happens.
Paulson told Fusco he'd
received the fake ID.
and Kruger's banking information
in an anonymous package.
Same as Karen Mills.
Someone's giving these
victims everything
they need to get back at Kruger.
It's turnkey revenge.
How many people in
that class action?
Over 200. 23 in
the tri-state area.
Finch, we can't stop that many.
It'd be fun trying.
I gotta ask, though, is
this guy even worth our time?
You know, that's not a question
we entertained when we saved you,
Ms. Shaw.
Our only chance to save
Kruger is to find him.
I'm sending you his coordinates.
Guy's a member of
the Northside Killas.
Dang, got shot up pretty bad.
Who do you think did this?
Hard to say.
I'd talk to his
regular customers first,
see who he was
having problems with.
But that's not our job.
We just secure the scene
and take the statements.
Right.
First body?
Yeah.
You okay?
Yeah, fine.
Rookies.
I don't know what happened.
No? Take a look at your shoes.
Just suck on the ice.
You find anything?
I haven't looked yet. Hang on.
Let's see.
What is it?
The file's been frozen.
What? Why?
Why do you think? Probably
too many prying eyes.
I'm feeling a little better,
so if you want to
get back to it--
Yeah, sure. Let's go.
Okay, Finch, I've got him.
Mr. Collier, it's
Wayne Kruger again.
I'm really hoping that we
can meet before you leave town
so I can explain the
confusion earlier today.
If you give me a chance, I'm
sure we can sort this all out.
Those crying the
loudest about privacy
are probably the ones
trying to hide something.
Finch.
They've hacked the car.
You can't fight the technology.
Someone is overriding
the vehicle's
electronic control unit.
You can't fight the technology.
Mr. Reese, they can take control
of his steering and throttle.
Bet you could use a lift.
Where am I?
Somewhere you won't be attacked
by the people who are
trying to kill you.
And you are?
Right now, your only option.
My car, what happened?
This electronic control unit,
it overrode your
car's internal E.C.U.,
allowing someone to control the
vehicle's functions remotely.
Someone who?
One of the members of that class
action suit brought against you.
That suit? My lawyers settled that.
Not to everyone's
satisfaction, it would seem.
That's interesting.
What?
Chloe Harper, the young
woman killed by her stalker.
Her mother was lead plaintiff, but
there was no mention of her father.
I just looked him up.
Stu Sommers.
Different last name
than Chloe's--divorced?
I remember that man
from your building.
He was posing as a janitor.
Yeah, Carl, hasn't
been around that long.
Because until three
months ago, he worked
as an electrical engineer
at an aerospace firm.
With a pedigree like that,
he would have the skills
to design these
sophisticated attacks.
We need to find him.
He must be staying
somewhere in the city.
His personnel file, it would
have to have an address.
I can call tomorrow morning.
Not necessary.
Are you hacking my
building's servers?
Do you mind?
Carl Miller, 162 Willow
Street, apartment 4, Brooklyn.
He'll either be there or
he'll be at Life Trace,
where he has access
to the computers.
Planning his next
attack. I'll check it out.
I'll hit the apartment.
Perhaps you should
rest, Mr. Kruger.
You've had quite a day.
Got anything to eat around here?
Just sencha green tea and
a box of doggie treats.
I don't suppose what
you're working on
over there concerns me.
I'm trying to
triangulate the location
of the call you
received in the elevator.
Did you recognize
anything about the caller?
No, nothing.
I'd prefer you didn't do that.
I'd prefer you mind
your own business.
That's a tad ironic, coming
from a man of your profession.
- Meaning what?
- Meaning your business
is minding everyone
else's business.
I do what I do to simplify and
improve other people's lives.
What is it that you do?
We help people out of
difficult situations,
even situations of
their own design.
So it's my fault that some
wacko's trying to kill me?
The man lost his
daughter, Mr. Kruger,
to a stalker who was
aided by your service.
You feel no accountability?
I'm part of a $300
billion-a-year industry.
Information abuses are
unfortunate, but they happen.
- can't be helped.
- Oh, they can,
but only if the people who
have access to the information
are as interested in protecting it
as they are in profiting from it.
I was just checking to
see if my wife had called.
I want to make sure she was okay.
Mr. Kruger, I didn't
want you using the phone
because it might not be safe,
but if you must
check your messages,
We can go through your
phone carrier's web portal.
Need my password?
You have a message.
Mr. Kruger, Pete Collier.
I spoke with my
colleagues and they agreed
we should all sit down again.
If you could meet us
at the Mayfield at 9:30,
that should give us enough
time before our flight.
We'll meet you in
the east dining room.
Yes, yes! If I leave
now, I can still make it.
And what about your wife?
I'll call her on the way.
Mr. Kruger, wait.
The message, it's
not labeled as "New".
Someone else must have
listened to it first.
Who?
Sommers!
And if he's listened to it, he'll
be waiting for you at the hotel.
It's too dangerous.
I don't care, there's too
much riding on this deal.
All right, I'll
contact my associates,
Then have them meet
us at the hotel.
Okay, okay, Bear.
Goodness.
Finch.
Mr. Reese... Kruger's gone.
I made the mistake of
turning my back on him.
Are you all right?
I will be.
It would appear that
Bear slowed Kruger down.
He's making his way
to the Mayfield Hotel
to take a meeting with
the Riverton people.
I believe that Sommers
knows that as well.
I'm at his locker now.
He's been stalking Kruger,
just like his own
daughter was stalked.
And ultimately killed.
I'll get over to the Mayfield.
Something else, Mr. Reese.
Kruger's not only
a potential victim,
he may also now be a perpetrator.
I cannot believe this is happening!
Someone is screwing with
me. Can't you see that?
I'm gonna fix this.
Looking for someone? Easy.
I won't miss at this range.
So what was the plan?
Were you gonna take me out
before or after my meeting?
I hadn't decided yet.
You know, you've caused me
a great deal of pain and
suffering, Mr. Sommers.
That was the point.
Now, you're gonna help
me get it all back.
Mr. Kruger, you got my message.
What...happened to you?
You know, I'm...
really glad you asked.
Where's the rest of your team?
Unfortunately, they had
to catch an earlier flight.
They send their regrets.
Hello.
Yeah. This is Mr. Sommers.
Look, I thought we were
gonna discuss our deal.
Yes, well, shortly
after I called you.
We attempted to revisit
the issue with our CEO,
but we couldn't get him
to reconsider his decision.
What?
I'm sorry, I thought
a face-to-face
would be better than
another phone call.
No.
- Excuse me?
- No!
You have no idea what I've
been through to get here!
Mr. Kruger, why do you have a gun?
Because this man humiliated
me, stole from me,
and even tried to kill me.
It was his twisted little game
that made our deal fall apart.
- Tell him.
- Okay, just, let's put down the gun.
I said tell him!
Don't do it, Mr. Sommers.
Who are you?
Someone who knows
what this is about.
Chloe.
Then you know he killed her,
and something had to be done.
I never touched your daughter.
You may not have put your hands
on her like that monster did,
but you're just as guilty.
I didn't do anything!
Exactly.
See, her ex-boyfriend
found her three times--
three times, using your Life Trace.
And every time he found her,
we asked the company to
take her information down,
and they didn't do it,
and so he found her again,
and again, until the last
time when he killed her.
All because you and your
company didn't do anything.
I didn't know.
I'm sorry.
Yeah?
Sorry isn't good enough.
Listen to me, Stu.
You do this, and your life...
it's over.
It's already over.
Stu...
this isn't the way to honor
your daughter's memory.
Think about it. What
would Chloe want?
You did the right
thing, for both of you.
Mr. Reese, I triangulated the call
that Kruger received
in the elevator.
It's now coming from
inside the Mayfield.
Mr. Reese?
You were right.
Something had to be done,
Which is why we reached
out to you, Mr. Sommers.
You--you did it. You
sent me the package.
We sent you the means to exact
justice for your daughter,
and you had the courage to act.
Unfortunately, the car
crash wasn't successful...
Requiring this improvisation,
but everything
worked out in the end.
You should go now, Mr. Sommers.
I think you understand now.
Understand what?
What is lost when your
privacy's stripped away.
Your identity, your job,
your family,
security, everything.
You...
And thousands more just like me.
People who have chosen
action over apathy,
to take back what men like you
and the government have stolen.
This wasn't a game, Mr. Kruger,
this was a lesson,
the first.
We were just gonna
scare you, but...
that wouldn't change
anything, would it?
Finch.
John, are you shot?
My vest caught it.
Think my rib's broken.
And Kruger?
He's dead, Finch.
I got him.
Can you walk?
I need to get to Collier.
We've got to get you out of here.
She's right, Mr.
Reese. Another time.
Back for more?
I need to say something.
Can it wait until
after you buy me coffee?
I know you had to take a
partner to get back on days,
but did you know
that two other rookies
were supposed to be
in this seat before me?
And both requested
to be reassigned.
If you want another
F.T.O., just say the word.
No, that's the point, I
didn't ask to be reassigned,
because I chose you.
Chose me? Why?
In the academy, I heard about you.
Your work with the
homicide task force
and how you took down
those corrupt cops.
I thought,
"Someday, that's
what I want to do."
That's why I jumped at the
chance to train under you.
But I don't get the sense
that you want to train anybody,
and if that's the case,
then I'd prefer it if
you just cut me loose.
3-Adam-10, we got a report of
a 10-53 near Morris and 149th.
Roger, dispatch.
3-adam-10 responding.
I made a call to
Riverton's home office.
Seems Collier, no doubt an alias,
has not returned to work.
And I don't think he will.
He started four months ago
as V.P. of customer analytics,
a position that allowed him
to get close enough to Kruger
so that he could both
witness and participate
in the dismantling of his life.
He told Kruger there
were others like him.
Yes, and I'm inclined
to believe him.
I discovered that
the anonymous packages
sent to Mr. Sommers and the others
came through
mail-processing centers
scattered all over the country.
Could've saved on the postage
and just shot him when
they had the chance.
I'm just saying it
was an elaborate plan.
It wasn't just
about killing Kruger.
It was about giving the people
he hurt a chance at retribution.
And also putting an
ideology into action.
Collier referred to Kruger's
murder as "A lesson".
The first.
I fear that whatever
his organization's
ultimate goals may be,
this could be just the beginning.